字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Now then, what do I do?
那麼我該怎麼做？
How do I protect my country from these animals?
我該怎麼避免這些蠢貨 侵略我的國家？
For the successful rescue of the prince,
你在危難中救出王子
you are granted 50 pounds of silver.
陛下賞賜你50磅銀子
Accept it with honor.
快謝過陛下
I was told you fought valiantly to ensure Canute's safe return.
我聽說你為了庫奴特奮戰
I am deeply grateful.
這是你應得的賞賜
Your Majesty, I humbly accept your gift.
是，謝陛下，小的就收下了
I expect great things from you in our fight to subjugate Wales.
我期待在威爾斯討伐時 你也能大顯身手
So, the sly, old fox figured it out after all.
這隻老狐狸果然還是察覺到了
Your Majesty,
殿下
please forgive me for speaking out of place.
請恕在下直言
Regarding the upcoming campaign in Wales…
這次討伐威爾斯
are you certain that this is the best decision?
真的是最好的決定嗎？
I believe the Wales campaign next spring
我認為明年春天討伐威爾斯
will only bring you a minimal benefit.
對丹麥軍隊來說幾乎毫無益處
I advise you to reconsider.
請陛下三思
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
I order him to create no friction.
不是說要暫時避免任何衝突嗎？
So this is Askeladd.
他就是阿謝拉特？
To directly contradict the king to his face…
竟然敢當面反對國王的決定…
He's got some nerve.
膽子真大
Forgive me, Your Highness.
抱歉，殿下
But Wales is the one thing I just cannot forgo.
威爾斯是我唯一無法退讓的
Explain your reasoning.
說說你的看法
Thank you, Your Highness.
謝陛下
First of all, we have just spent ten years fighting the English.
首先，這十年來 我們不停與英格蘭作戰
Right now, I believe we should be
我認為我們現在應該
recovering the losses of the country and the people.
建設新領土和補充兵力 以彌補之前的損失
Then, there is also the matter of Wales's harsh and poor landscape.
第二，威爾斯地勢險峻且土地貧瘠
It would be like whipping tired horses to chase a rabbit
進行討伐就像是 鞭策疲累的馬去追趕兔子
and end up stepping off a cliff.
最後只會掉落懸崖而已
In short, the conquest of Wales is not worth the effort.
總而言之，攻打威爾斯一點都不划算
-That's true. -He makes a good point.
-沒錯 -他說得有道理
He does have a way with words.
他真的很會講話
It is not a conquest.
這不是攻打
We must ensure that the insolent know their place.
重點是不能放任那些無禮之徒 繼續囂張下去
Make no mistake.
別誤會了
If you are worried about their actions…
如果是擔心他們會有什麼行動
please allow me to be your envoy.
那請任命我為使者
I will show you that the Welsh can indeed be convinced.
我一定能說服威爾斯人對陛下稱臣
Are you telling the king he must humble himself a third time
你是要我這個國王 三度低聲下氣去問他們嗎？
to those whom you would call "rabbits"?
對方可是你所謂的兔子
Precisely because it is a third time,
正因為去了三次
Your Majesty's magnanimity will be conveyed to them.
他們應該能感受到陛下寬大的心胸
I beg you to heed my advice.
求陛下採納我的建議
Oh, he's in for it now.
他要殺了他嗎？
This is what a loyal vassal looks like.
這就是忠臣該有的樣子
There is no greater treasure to a king than a remonstrance.
對國王來說，沒有比諫言更寶貴的了
My army is replete with truly brave men like him.
看來我軍隊中的每個人都很忠勇
Your praises are wasted on me.
陛下過獎了
Well, that's boring.
真無聊
Continue to lend me your strength.
繼續為我效命吧
Wales or Canute. Choose.
威爾斯還是庫奴特，你自己選
To be honest, I have little care for Wales.
老實說，我一點都不在乎威爾斯
Give me Canute's head and come to my side.
交出庫奴特的腦袋，為我效命
Do so, and I will overlook Wales.
我就放過威爾斯
I did some research on you.
我打聽了你的背景
It seems your mother was a slave after all.
看來你的母親確實是奴隸
I have a guess as to why you are so insistent about Wales.
你對威爾斯這麼堅持的原因不難猜測
It seems the people
看來那裡的特產
from that country really are slaves.
就只有奴隸
What do you think? It's still ready for action.
你覺得如何？還很穩固喔
It's the ship you've always wanted to sail on.
你以前老是想登上這艘船
I'm finally letting you board it.
我現在終於要讓你上船了
Just rest until Mols and the others return.
先休息一下，等莫爾斯他們回來
-Hurry and take this. -All right.
-快把這個收起來 -好
Come on! Be careful!
你在做什麼？小心！
Yes, sir.
是
You must be starved.
你一定很餓吧
Just wait. I've got some great beef jerky.
等一下，我有上等的牛肉乾
Thorfinn!
托爾芬！
Where did you go? Thorfinn!
你在哪裡？托爾芬！
Thorfinn.
托爾芬…
What a disgraceful face.
這張臉真討人厭
To let the crown rest atop a face like that
王冠戴在你這種人的頭上
is unforgivable.
我實在看不下去
-What? -Did he just say that to the king?
什麼？
What did you just say?
你剛剛說什麼？
Have you gone def you old bastard?
你連耳朵都聾了嗎？你這個老頭
I said a shining crown shouldn't be worn by ugly filth.
我說醜八怪不配戴上金光閃閃的王冠
What?
什麼？
You do not have the face of a king.
你沒有王者之風
Gurads, stand down!
衛兵都別動！
The king
國王可是在我的劍所能及的範圍內
Is he serious?
他是來真的嗎？
Good Gods.
喂…
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
You bastard! King Sweyn is my--!
混蛋，斯韋恩王是我的獵物…
Don't move, Thorkell!
托魯克爾，不准動！
Askeladd is not himself!
阿謝拉特現在不正常！
Do not provoke him!
不要刺激他！
Lower your sword.
把劍放下
Do so, and I will forgive this impertinence.
我這次可以原諒你的無禮
Forgive?
原諒？
Don't get carried away, you barbarian.
你這個野蠻人別太得意忘形了
For the mockery of my family and my people,
你貶低我的家人和我們人民
you deserve certain death!
罪該萬死！
This is your final warning.
這是最後一次警告
Lower your sword.
把劍放下，阿謝拉特
That is an epithet.
那只是我的綽號
I will tell you the true name bestowed upon me by my mother.
我就把我母親替我取的真名告訴你吧
Lucius Artorius Castus.
魯基烏斯阿托利斯卡斯托斯
I am
我才是
the rightful king and ruler of all Britannia.
不列顛尼亞這塊土地的正統國王
Men attack!
來人，趁現在！
That felt good.
真是痛快
Now then…
好了…
Why aren't you attacking? Get him!
你們在等什麼？快點…
After him, men!
全都上去把他拿下！
This fiend has killed the king!
他可是弒君的大罪人！
Execute him!
殺了他！
Hey, what's going on?
喂，怎麼回事？
What?
什麼…
What the hell is he doing?
他在做什麼？
What is happening in there?
到底發生什麼事？
How dare you, idiot!
那個白痴！
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Whoever wants to die next, come forward!
想死的人就往前啊！
The king of Britannia will kill you himself!
不列顛尼亞國王會親自殺了你！
Faulter notl! Overwhelm him with your numbers!
別怕，利用人數優勢來壓制他！
Die!
去死吧！
Hurry up!
快點！
Don't push!
不要推！
-Get out! -Stop pushing!
-你才不要推！ -好痛！
Move!
讓開！
Damn it. Out of the way!
可惡，閃邊去！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Endure it, Thorkell.
忍耐一下，托魯克爾
Wait your turn.
還沒輪到你
That doesn't matter anymore!
我不管了
He's lost his mind.
他瘋了
What I hate most is when someone snatches my prey.
我最討厭有人搶走我的獵物
He hasn't lost his mind.
他並沒有發瘋
That's just an act.
他只是在演戲而已
What?
什麼？
He merely chose to save both me and Wales.
他只是選擇同時救我和威爾斯
Acting like he's mad is his way of taking blame for murdering the king.
假裝抓狂是為了要獨自攬下弒君之罪
For now, let him rampage. I'll let you land the finishing blow.
再讓他發洩一下吧
I don't care.
我才不管
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
You say he is your vassal.
他是你的手下
The owner of a mad dog should be the one to put him down.
狗惹的禍要由主人自己善後
What's wrong, you Danish bastards?
你們這些丹麥混蛋怎麼了？
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
You bastard.
你這個混蛋
Do you understand what you've done?
你知道自己幹了什麼事嗎？
You murdered the king!
你殺了國王！
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
I'm here, alive and well.
本王還在這裡活得好好的
Shut the hell up!
給我閉嘴！
You bastard son of a slave!
你這個奴隸生的王八蛋！
You piece of shit.
你這混帳…
Is that any way to speak to your king?
這是對國王說話該有的態度嗎？
Kneel before me!
給我跪下！
I'll let you have the honor of kissing my boot
我就賞你這個榮譽來舔我的鞋子
and dying!
然後受死！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Stay back, Thorfinn!
托爾芬，不要過來！
Is this your first time stabbing someone, Prince?
這是你第一次殺人嗎，王子？
Well done.
做得好
Hey! Askeladd!
喂，阿謝拉特！
Hey, look!
你們看！
What?
什麼？
He killed him?
他殺了他？
The prince did it!
王子殿下殺了他！
Stand up properly.
站好
This is important.
現在是重要關頭
The stage is set for you.
舞台都已經為你設好
Don't waste it.
別浪費了
Get up, you old geezer!
喂，光頭！
What are you doing here taking a casual nap?
你悠閒地躺在這裡幹嘛？
Damn it! Goddamn it all!
可惡，該死的！
You got yourself stabbed in the the heart, you moron!
你被刺中要害了，混蛋！
My God, you are such a pain.
真是麻煩
Just let me rest a while.
讓我休息一下吧
Bastard! Stand up now!
王八蛋，快站起來！
We're getting out of here!
我帶你離開這裡
You fool.
你這傻子
Hurry and finish me off.
快給我個痛快吧
I'm sorry for making you wait.
抱歉讓你久等了
Kill me.
殺了我
We are
你我是敵人，不是嗎？
You're going to die?
你要死了嗎？
You?
你？
You must hurry then.
快點
There's no time left.
沒時間了
Are you mocking me?
你在小看我嗎？
You bastard!
混蛋！
This isn't supposed to happen!
不應該發生這種事的！
The way we settle things
我跟你的決鬥
isn't supposed to happen like this!
不該像這樣子的！
I won't forgive you!
我不會原諒你的！
Don't just die!
不准你就這樣死掉！
Stand up!
站起來！
Duel me right now!
立刻跟我決鬥！
I'm the one who's supposed to kill you!
要打敗你的人應該是我！
Hey, come on! Stop messing around!
快起來！別鬧了！
-Good grief. -Stand up!
-真是的 -站起來！
This is why I don't like kids…
難怪我不喜歡小孩子…
Duel me! Get up!
跟我決鬥，喂！
How do you
你打算怎麼生活？
From now into the future,
從今以後
long after I've died,
在我死後
how do you intend to live,
你打算過什麼樣的生活，托爾芬？
You haven't even thought that far ahead.
你根本沒想過吧
Shut up.
閉嘴
Stop this nonsense and just move on.
別再鬧了，向前看吧
Doing this forever…
不停地做這種事…
will only keep you stuck in this worthless place.
只會讓你被困在無用的牢籠裡
Go far, far away.
前進吧，去遠方
Go even beyond the land where Thors went, son of Thors.
超越托爾茲所到的世界，托爾茲之子
That is your…
那才是…
true fight.
你真正的戰鬥
Become a true warrior…
成為真正的戰士
son of Thors.
成為托爾茲之子
Thorfinn, I won't ask you to forgive me.
托爾芬，我不指望你原諒我
He was punished
我之所以殺他
for suddenly going mad and murdering the king.
是因為他突然抓狂，殺死國王
Therefore,
不過
I believe you do not wish to serve me anymore.
事已至此 你應該不會想繼續替我效命了
I release you from my service.
你想去哪裡都可以
-Kill him! -He's a traitor, too!
-殺了他！ -他也是叛徒！
Stop!
住手！
Do not kill him!
不准殺他！
Step back!
全都退後！
I will decide his punishment!
他的懲罰由我決定！
Thorkell.
托魯克爾，沒事的
Being cut
只是被劃一刀
is a light reparation.
這點代價算很輕了
Your Highness.
殿下
Let us tend to your wound.
請到後面的房間包紮傷口吧
Let me handle things from here.
這裡讓我來處理
Escort the prince!
護送王子！
Floki.
弗洛基
With the death of the late king,
先王駕崩之後
who do you regard as commander-in-chief of England's field army now?
你覺得在英格蘭的軍隊該由誰指揮？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Speak your mind.
你直說吧
Men, listen to me.
各位，聽我說
The late King Sweyn has passed away.
先王斯韋恩陛下已經駕崩
From now,
從現在起
the role of commander of all armies and ruler of England
所有軍隊的指揮權 以及英格蘭的統治權
belongs to me, Canute!
全都屬於我，庫奴特！
The subjugation of Wales is suspended.
討伐威爾斯一事就此打住
With the death of the late king,
先王的死訊傳出之後
the surviving English soldiers will mount a revolt.
英格蘭軍隊的餘黨可能會反抗
We must prepare for this first.
我們首先得為此做好準備
We will continue the reward ceremony at a later time.
尚未公佈的賞賜之後再繼續
That is all.
就這樣
You are dismissed.
解散
-Hey! -Come on!
-喂！ -快點！
Stop already!
住手！
-You…
-來吧！ -你…